nelnet.com 2005-06-11

# Privacy Statement

**_Nelnet’s Privacy Policies_**

We’d like you to know about our privacy policies and practices, and how we protect your personal information. Please read our privacy policies below. 

Nelnet Privacy Policy – Online Information  
This Policy tells you how we collect and use information from our online customers and visitors. 

Nelnet Privacy Policy – Consumer Information  
This Policy explains our collection and use practices regarding consumer information, including how and what we share with our related companies and with outside companies. 

The privacy policies on this Web site apply to users who are located in the U.S. when visiting our Web sites. The policies are subject to change from time to time, so be sure to check back occasionally to ensure you have read the most current version. 

To the extent our policies differ for different products and services on a particular Web site, those differences will be detailed on that Web site. 

**Nelnet Privacy Policy – Online Information**

We at Nelnet are committed to providing you a useful and enjoyable online experience, and to protecting your personal information during your visit. When you access a Nelnet Web site, you can be sure that your information is protected by the latest security and authentication techniques. We may collect information from your visit, in order to personalize and improve upon your experience with us, but all information we collect is treated as confidential. 

To access student loan account information and send emails via our Web site, you will need a browser that supports the use of Secure Sockets Layer (Netscape 4.0 or greater, MS Internet Explorer 5.0 or greater, etc). This encryption technology helps ensure the authenticity of your online sessions and secures data being transmitted over the public Internet. 

If you are using Netscape Navigator, your session is secured if a key appears in the lower left corner of your screen; when the session is not secure, the key will appear broken. Internet Explorer displays a lock icon in a locked position on the status bar when you enter a secure site. When you leave a secure Web site, Internet Explorer displays a lock icon in an unlocked position on the status bar. If the page you are viewing uses frames, you may not see the key or lock, but can simply right-click anywhere in the frame and select “Properties”. If the Web site address (URL) starts with “https” the “s” indicates a secure site or area of the site. 

When you enter a Nelnet Web site, you will pass through our security "firewall" and we identify the Internet Protocol (IP) address of your computer or handheld device. The IP address won’t identify you personally, but it will let us identify the device you’re using and we store IP addresses in case we need to track a connection for security purposes. 

Nelnet Web sites use cookies in several applications for navigational purposes. A cookie is a small text file placed on your hard drive (with your permission) by a Web page server. Accepting a cookie from a Nelnet Web site does not give Nelnet access to your computer or any personal information about you. Also, the type of cookies we use don’t get stored permanently in your computer – they expire immediately after you close your browser and are deleted. You can also set up your Web browser to inform you when cookies are set or to prevent cookies from being set. 

If you supply us with your email address we may let you know by email about other products and services and product enhancements that may be of interest to you. You will have the opportunity to tell us you don’t want to receive future messages with each message you receive. If you send us an email question or comment, we will use your email address to reply to you and we will temporarily store your email address, your message and our reply for quality assurance or to satisfy applicable laws and regulations. When we collect your email address this way, we won’t use it for marketing our products and services unless you have given us permission. If you are not comfortable that your email system is secure, you can always contact Customer Service by telephone. 

We don't knowingly collect, maintain or use personal information from our Web sites about children under age 13. If we find out we have collected such information we will take all reasonable measures to delete that information from our system as soon as possible. We are not responsible for the collection and use of information by companies or individuals unaffiliated with us whose Web sites may contain links to ours, including vendors where you may shop. 

Please note that when you shop with a vendor who is linked to a Nelnet Web site, even though you may have started your visit at the Nelnet site, and even though Nelnet pages may still appear, your transactions are completed with a separate organization, not with Nelnet. We don’t share your personal information with them, but information you choose to share with them will fall under their privacy policies, which we encourage you to review. We carefully select other organizations in an effort to give you the value and excellent customer service you expect from Nelnet. 

We have also created relationships with others on the Web who might have products and services we do not, but that we think you might be interested in. These companies’ Web sites may be hyperlinked to ours, or we may have "co-branded" sites we share with them. Again, we do not share your personal information with them, nor do we control their use of your information. That’s why it is important for you to know what their privacy practices are if you visit their sites. 

**_Nelnet Privacy Policy – consumer information_**

Why we collect information | What we collect | How we use information | Security | The Nelnet Companies | E-mail preference

**Summary of our policy  
**Nelnet knows how important privacy is to you, and we are committed to providing you with extraordinary customer service. That commitment includes protecting personal information you entrust to us by adhering to strict guidelines. 

This policy explains the collection and use practices of the Nelnet Companies  regarding consumer information, including how and what we share with our related companies.  Nelnet does not share your personal information outside the Nelnet Companies except in the limited situations described below and we will never sell or provide your personal information to third parties for their own use. This policy is our standard regarding collection, use, retention, and security of nonpublic personal information. Even if you pay off your loan(s), we will continue to adhere to the privacy policies and practices described in this notice. 

You can direct us not to share “non-transactional” information with our affiliated Nelnet Companies.  This policy applies to you if you have received a financial product or service from one of the Nelnet Companies. The typical example of this is if a Nelnet company made, or purchased and now owns, your student loan. This policy also applies to our former customers. **Please note that if Nelnet services, but does not own, your student loan, your lender’s privacy policy applies instead**. In those cases, Nelnet complies with the privacy policies of our lender clients. The information in this policy applies to individuals only, and we may change the policies from time to time. The effective date of this policy is July 1, 2004. 

You can take additional steps to protect your privacy by keeping passwords and PIN’s confidential, never disclosing personal information to unknown callers, and ensuring your Internet use is secured and protected from unauthorized access or use.

**Why we collect information  
** We collect information so we can identify you as our customer, to establish, manage and protect your accounts, to complete your transactions, to create and offer you products and services you might be interested in, and to comply with various legal and regulatory requirements. 

**What information we collect  
**“Nonpublic personal information” is information about you that is not publicly available, but that we get in connection with providing a financial product or service to you, and that we need in order to serve you effectively and efficiently. We may collect nonpublic personal information about you in the following ways:

·      Information we receive from you on applications or other loan and account forms, which may include your name, address, e-mail address, birth date, and phone number, so we can identify you as a customer, get in touch with you about your account when necessary, and generally maintain your account. Other information may include your Social Security number or other identifying information which helps us prevent unauthorized access to or use of your account, and/or personal financial information that helps us process your application and identify products and services that may be of interest to you.

·      Information about your transactions with us, with our affiliates, or others, for example, account balances, your payment history, and how you use your account. We use this information to respond to your requests, service your accounts, and again, make recommendations or offers to you. 

·      Information we receive from third parties, such as credit bureaus.  This may include your credit history or credit score. This information is used in processing loan applications, collecting accounts, and determining eligibility for offers of other products and services.

·      Information you ask us to obtain from others, for example, information you authorize us to receive on your Federal loan application, promissory note, or other documents.

·      Information we collect when you use our Internet Web sites and services, send us e-mail messages, or register or apply for our products and services. **__**

**How we use information __**

_Within the Nelnet Companies_

The Nelnet Companies are involved in a variety of businesses related to helping families pay for higher education, including education lending  (funding, purchase, and sale of education loans), and loan servicing.  Among the Nelnet Companies, we may share transactional information about you in order to provide you a loan or to service your existing loan account.  This could include things such as: 

·          Your loan account balance, payment history, and the parties to your loan

·          Transactions with one or more of the Nelnet Companies

·          Information you include on a loan application, such as contact information, financial data, your assets, and income

This could also include non-transactional information about you, such as information we receive from credit bureaus or other nonaffiliated parties, such as your creditworthiness, your payment history, or your employment history. 

In either case, Nelnet will only use the information for reasons necessary to these functions. 

Except to the extent required to provide a service you have requested, you can direct us not to share the “non-transactional” type information, even within the Nelnet Companies.

_Outside the Nelnet Companies_

·          In limited situations, we may need to share your information with companies outside our organization in order to do business with you. For example:

o        Service providers and business partners. This includes companies that originate loans or process loan transactions for us, vendors that print, prepare or mail statements for us, other lenders, computer system programmers, and related vendors that help us deliver our products and services as efficiently and effective as possible; and 

o        Marketing service providers. These companies may be used to help us communicate information about products, services and special offers to you. 

·          We screen our potential outside business partners very carefully.  These providers only receive limited information about you as necessary to perform their functions. They are always required to maintain confidentiality of the information and we restrict their use to the purpose we authorize, and they are not allowed to pass the information on to others for their own benefit. 

In addition, from time to time, Nelnet may also send you information about products or services offered by reputable third parties that we believe will be of interest to our customers. **However, we will not share your personal information with these parties at any time.**

_Other situations_

Finally, sometimes the law or other circumstances also require that we disclose nonpublic personal information about you to nonaffiliated third parties. Some examples are: when you ask or permit us to do so; when a guaranty agency, school, or the Department of Education need that information in connection with your account, with agencies that assist us in servicing your loan; in response to subpoenas or court orders; with credit bureaus; or when we suspect fraud or criminal activity. 

**Our security procedures**

Nelnet takes careful steps to safeguard customer information. We restrict access to your personal and account information to those employees who need to know that information to provide products or services to you, and we regularly train our employees on privacy, information security, and their obligation to protect your information. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal and industry standards to guard your personal information, and we regularly test those safeguards to maintain the appropriate levels of protection. 

Our Corporate Technology division continually updates and improves the security standards and procedures we use to help protect against anyone gaining unauthorized access to your confidential information, including through the Internet. We also build checks and balances into our procedures so that we can properly identify our customers. 

As stated above, you can help safeguard your personal information by taking a few simple precautions. Protect your account numbers, passwords, PIN’s, and customer access numbers. Never disclose confidential information to unknown callers. You should always use a secure browser and current virus detection software, and never open e-mail from unknown sources. 

**The Nelnet Companies**

This policy applies to the Nelnet companies listed below, as well as trusts and special purpose entities created by these companies. This list may change from time to time without notice. 

Nelnet, Inc.  
  
---  
  
National Education Loan Network, Inc.  
  
Nelnet Guarantee Services, Inc.  
  
GuaranTec LLP  
  
Nelnet Marketing Solutions, Inc.  
  
Class Credit, Inc.  
  
InTuition, Inc.  
  
EFS, Inc  
  
EMT Corporation  
  
EFS Finance Co.  
  
MELMAC, Inc.  
  
Nelnet Mentor LLC  
  
National Education Loan of New England, Inc.  
  
BST Holdings, Inc.  
  
**Other helpful information**

Nelnet provides links to external sites as a convenience to the user. The inclusion of any link does not imply our endorsement of any other organization, its Web sites, or its products and/or services. Nelnet is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of any other Web site.

**Identity theft**  
If you believe you are a victim of identify theft:  

* Call the Federal Social Security Administration fraud hotline – 800.2610.0271
* File a police report with your local authorities, note the report number and officer’s name 
* Call the Federal Trade Commission’s Identity Theft hotline: 877.IDTHEFT
* Contact the major national credit reporting agencies: 
Experian 888.397.3742  
Equifax 800.525.6285  
Trans Union 800.680.7289  
Innovis 800.540.2505  

**National Do Not Call Registry**  
You can sign up here to have your telephone number included on the National Do Not Call registry that telemarketers are required to purchase and exclude from their calling campaigns:[ https://www.donotcall.gov/register/Reg.aspx](https://www.donotcall.gov/register/Reg.aspx)

**Credit Bureau lists**  
Credit reporting agencies may sell your personal information to companies for “pre-screened” credit offers – to prevent this practice, call the Credit Reporting Industry Pre-screening Opt Out number at **888.567.8688** and remove your name from their lists. 

**Direct marketing preferences  
** You can also limit other marketing you receive by contacting the Direct Marketing Association (DMA) at the addresses below and have your name removed from their contact lists. You must include your name, address, and telephone number with your request.

DMA Mail Preference Service | DMA Telephone Preference Service  
---|---  
PO Box 643 | PO Box 1559  
Carmel, NY 10512 | Carmel, NY 10512  
  
E-mail preference service: <http://dmaconsumers.org/optoutform_emps.shtml>********
